omniture.com 2010-06-11

# Omniture Privacy Center: Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

### Effective April 15, 2009

[](http://www.truste.com/ivalidate.php?url=www.omniture.com&sealid=103)Omniture and its subsidiaries (hereinafter “we”) have created this privacy policy (the "Site Policy") to describe the information practices of this Omniture website (www.omniture.com, the "Site"). Because we gather important information from visitors to the Site, we have established the Site Policy as a means to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Site. We will treat your personal information in accordance with the privacy statement in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise consent. By using the Site, you are agreeing to the terms of the Site Policy. We reserve the right to change the Site Policy. If we decide to make a material change to the Site Policy, we will post a notice on our home page at least thirty days prior to making any material changes. Your continued use of the Site, including use after the posting of any changes to these terms, will be deemed acceptance by you of the Site Policy. Please note that further information regarding our practices with regards to our products and services and the data collection methods used by our products and services, including cookies and web beacons, can be found at: 

  * Products and Services Privacy Statement
  * Omniture SiteCatalyst HBX Privacy Center. 

You will find information on the following topics within this Site Policy:

  * Collected Information
  * Cookies and Clear GIFs
  * Security
  * Third-Party Sites
  * Opt-Out & Update Policy
  * Partners and Programs

## Collected Information

**Anonymous Information**  
You can visit the Site to read information about our company, products, and services without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information. To improve the usefulness of the Site, we measure and analyze non-identifying, aggregate usage, and volume statistical information from Site visitors in order to administer the Site, and to constantly improve the quality of our service and site performance, such as providing more relevant content to you during your visit(s). 

Information gathered may include, but is not limited to, the following: the activity of the Site visitor’s browser when the visitor is viewing the Site; the site path of visitors; general information regarding the visitor’s internet service provider and host, and the time visitors come to the Site. We reserve the right to publish anonymous, aggregate summary information regarding Site visitors for promotional purposes and as a representative audience for advertisers. Please note that this is not personal information, only general summaries of our visitors’ usage of the Site. 

**Personally Identifiable Information**  
You may wish to request information about our products and services. To facilitate the distribution of this content, you are asked to provide information, such as, but not limited to, name, company, title, phone number, e-mail address, site name, URL, and address. Based on the your request, we may also ask for additional information, such as number of page views your company’s site receives, how many orders your company’s site receives, and how you heard about us. This information is provided by you on a voluntary basis only and is not required by us in order for you to use and enjoy the Site.

We may also collect log-in information, such as user name and account name, of our customers’ internal users that log-in to products on the Site. Such user information may be associated with a user’s individual visitation activity whether or not he/she is logged-in to the products at such time.

**Third Party Personally Identifiable Information**  
In the log in portion of the site, site administrators will have permission to enter third party information, such as email address and name to create accounts for the users. This information is only used for the purpose intended and for no other purpose.

**Information Use and Disclosure**  
We may use the information that we collect on the Site to contact you to further discuss your interest in our company, our services, and to send information regarding our company or partners, such as marketing promotions and events. This information may also be used to improve the services we provide to you and your company. The information is collected and stored in a manner that we determine is appropriate for the nature of the data that we collect, and the need to fulfill your request. This information is not provided to third parties for their own use, unless specifically authorized by you. The Company does not share, sell, rent, or trade PII with third parties for their promotional purposes.

We use third party service providers to provide automated data processing, marketing automation, data appends, contact discovery, and delivery services on the Site for our own purposes. When you sign up for certain of our services, we may share your personally identifiable information as necessary for one or more third parties to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

We may disclose personal information when required by law, or in order to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on the Site. Certain personal information that we collect on the Site may be distributed among ourselves or other third parties solely for the purposes of processing your request or arranging delivery of your subscription, product, or service that you have requested. We may store and process personal information in the United States or any other country in which we (or any of our agents) maintain facilities. 

**Blogs and Testimonials**  
If you use a blog on the Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. Some of our clients have chosen to post testimonials on our site. The user has provided approval to post their personally identifiable information along with this testimonial. 

Back to top

## Cookies and clear GIFs

**What Are Cookies**   
Cookies are files that web servers place on an Internet user’s computer that are designed to store basic information (such as visitor preferences). The use of cookies on the Site allows visitors to enjoy more seamless visits and more accurately measures visitor behavior on the Site. There are two types of cookies that we may use: session and persistent. Session cookies exist only during an Internet user’s online session. They disappear from the user’s computer when he/she closes the browser software. Persistent cookies remain on the user’s computer after the browser has been closed. The cookies used on the Site do not identify you personally. They merely recognize your browser, unless you choose to identify yourself voluntarily. You may choose to identify yourself for any one of the following reasons: by asking the browser to remember your username and password, by responding to a promotional offer, or by personalizing a web page or requesting more information on a product or service. 

**How We Use Cookies**   
When you interact with the Site, we strive to make that experience easy, meaningful, and relevant. When you come to the Site, our web server uses cookies to improve your interaction with the Site by, for example, remembering your preferences and dynamically serving more relevant content to you. More specifically, we use cookies to measure your behavior on the Site and to save personal settings on specific pages. For our customers who login to our products through the Site, cookies can also be used to save the username so that we can process the saved login information and quickly log that user into the product. Cookies also help us make sure you are who you say you are after you've logged in. We may link personal information that you have submitted on the Site with our cookies that are associated with your visit(s) to the Site in order to provide more relevant content to you during your visit(s). We use cookies (that only we can read and use) to identify the fact that you are one of our customers or a prior Site visitor (as applicable). Visitors who disable their web browsers' ability to accept cookies will still be able to browse the Site; however, they may lose some of the functionality provided by the use of cookies. When examining your cookies you may notice a cookie that is set by the following domains: 2o7.net, omtrdc.net, and omniture.com. The 2o7.net and omtrdc.net domains are used for data collection and are the primary domains we use to measure visitor behavior on this Site. The omtrdc.net domain is also used to serve relevant and visitor tailored content during the visitor’s session. The omniture.com domain is the primary domain we use to store visitor preferences and campaign attributes, and also to serve dynamic and relevant content to visitors of this Site.

**Controlling Our Use of Cookies**  
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you are using a public computer or do not otherwise want this information to be stored, you can select the appropriate radio button on the sign-in page, and this cookie will not be used. For further information about disabling cookies you can visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to login or use other interactive features of our websites and services that depend on cookies. 

**What are Clear Gifs?**   
Clear gifs (also known as web beacons) are used in combination with cookies to help Site operators understand how visitors interact with their websites. A clear gif is typically a transparent graphic image (usually 1 pixel x 1 pixel) that is placed on a site. The use of a clear gif allows the Site to measure the actions of the visitor opening the page that contains the clear gif. 

**How We Use Clear Gifs**   
We utilize clear gifs to measure visitor behavior, to help us improve visitor experience, and to manage site content. We, and our Subsidiaries, may use clear gifs on this Site, in our e-mails, in our advertisements on other web sites, or in our advertisements in others' e-mails. 

Back to top

## Security

The Site has physical, administrative and technical measures in place to maintain the security, confidentiality, and integrity of the data under our control, and to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of such data. For example, when the Site is accessed using Netscape Navigator, Microsoft Internet Explorer versions 5.0, or higher, Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology protects information using both server authentication and data encryption to help ensure that the data is safe, secure, and available only to our customers and us. In addition, we use secured server areas and advanced firewall technology to minimize the risk of security breaches for individually identifiable information that is volunteered on the Site. Finally, we provide unique usernames and passwords that must be entered each time a customer, or one of our employees that has a business need to access the information, logs on to one of our products via the Site. These safeguards help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and help ensure the appropriate use of all data. 

While we strive to protect your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure and therefore we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you send to us. You send any information via the Site at your own risk.

Back to top

## Third party sites

The Site contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites. Customers and visitors should check the privacy policy statements of these other websites to understand their policies. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential.

Back to top

## Opt-out and update policies

**Opt-Out Policy:**  
We offer visitors to the Site a means for controlling the use of session information. If, at any time after registering for information or ordering our services, you change your mind about receiving information from us or about the use of information volunteered by you, please send us a request specifying your new choice. To opt out of marketing or promotional emails, please either click unsubscribe in the body of the email communication or go to <http://www.omniture.com/unsubscribe> to be removed. If you do not wish to allow your session visitation information on the Site to be aggregated and analyzed by us, you may utilize the following opt out mechanism.  Click Here To Opt-Out Now. In addition, if you do not wish to allow your session visitation information to be used for receiving dynamic content via the Site tailored to your specific interests during your session on this Site, you may utilize the following opt out mechanism.  Click Here To Opt-Out Now. 

**Updating Your Information:**  
We provide all visitors to the Site options for reviewing, changing, deleting and modifying personally identifiable information previously provided. To update your organization's profile, user profiles, billing information or to discontinue the Service, please e-mail [update@omniture.com](mailto:update@omniture.com). You can expect to receive a response to any such update request within thirty (30) days of our receipt of the same.

We will provide you with a copy of any personal information that you have provided in connection with your visit to the Site should you request it, but will require evidence of your identity. We may require a nominal administration fee to cover our costs in providing such information. If you wish to access the personal information we have about you, or to correct factual errors in our records, please contact us as set forth in the "Contact Us" section below. To protect your privacy, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

**Contact Us:**  
If you have questions, concerns, or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, you should first contact our Privacy Department by e-mail at [privacy@omniture.com](mailto:privacy@omniture.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of their inquiry or their inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, then you may contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process (<http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint>). TRUSTe serves as a liaison with the Site to help resolve user concerns. 

We may also be reached at the contact information on our Contact Us page. Our physical address is 550 East Timpanogos Circle, Orem, Utah 84097.

Back to top

## Partners and programs

### TRUSTe

We are a Participant in the TRUSTe Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to advance privacy and trust in the networked world. As the Site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices monitored for compliance by TRUSTe. This privacy statement covers the Site [www.Omniture.com] and any and all sub-domains thereof. The TRUSTe program does not cover personally identifiable information that may be collected through software downloaded through the Site, including any subdomains. Because the Site owners (i.e. Omniture and its subsidiaries) want to demonstrate its commitment to users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

We participate in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the Safe Harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at <http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint>, fax at +1 415-520-3420, or mail at Watchdog Complaints, TRUSTe, 55 2nd Street, Second Floor, San Francisco, CA, USA 94105. If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe’s dispute resolution process, see <http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint> or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English. For human resources data we have agreed to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities. Any questions, comments or complaints about the data practices (including without limitation compliance with data privacy principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, access, security, data integrity, or enforcement) of a hosted online OnBoarding software customer or partner for whom we process data should be addressed to that customer or partner. More information about the United States Department of Commerce Safe Harbor program, including the principles set forth above, can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

We are compliant with the BBBOnLine(R) Privacy standards and are fully authorized to display the BBBOnLine Privacy Seal. By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine Privacy Program we have made a commitment to meet the programs' strict requirements regarding how we treat your information and have it verified by BBBOnLine as required. Businesses that qualify for the BBBOnLine Privacy Seal are demonstrating the care and respect they have for the treatment of personal data. Further information about this program is available at [http://www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.com/). 

Back to top
